A Guide to the Alexandra Ripley Additional Papers, 1977,1995-1996
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Alexandra Ripley Additional Papers 1977, 1995-1996
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10624-j
This collection consists of ca. 104 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The permission of Alexandra Ripley is required for access to the collection, copying, and all quotations.
Acquisition Information
These papers were loaned to the University of Virginia Library by Alexandra Ripley, Keswick, Virginia, on October 1, 1996.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of ca. 104 items (9 Hollinger boxes, ca. 3 linear shelf feet), ca. 1977, 1995-1996, chiefly pertaining to the research and writing of Alexandra Ripley's novel A Love Divine about Joseph of Arimathea. The papers include research notes and reference books, autograph and typed manuscripts, drafts and a final copyedited typescript, two oversize poster illustrations of the Temple Mount in Jerusalem and of the city itself, an advance reading copy of the novel, and some faxed correspondence between Ripley and her editor, Carolyn Blakemore. Also present is an electrostatic copy of a two page autograph discussion of "The Saga of Scarlett" by Alexandra Ripley, a critique of the original manuscript for Scarlett, the manuscript for Scarlett Story by Jim Henerson and Christopher Lofton, RHI Productions, based on the novel by Alexandra Ripley, and a typed manuscript of Scarlett, including a folder of miscellaneous pages.
Contents List
- AMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Chapters 1-101, with changes & corrections (7 folders) ca. 1995 (Box 1)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Chapters 1-101, Typescript with autograph inserts and changes (6 folders) ca. 1995 (Box 2)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, N.Y. Working Typescript, Chapters 1-61, with changes & corrections (3 folders) [1995?], n.d. (Box 3)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Chapters 1-20, with corrections and changes, including faxes from Carolyn Blakemore (2 folders) 1995 Dec-1996 Jan (Box 3)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Chapters 21-38, with corrections and changes, including faxes from Carolyn Blakemore 1995 Dec-1996 Jan (Box 4)
- TMs (EC) A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Chapters 1-84 (4 folders) 1996 Feb 22 (Box 4)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley - Final Copyedited Typescript, Chapters 1-85 (5 folders) 1996 Mar 19 (Box 5)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Chapters 62-84, Pages 663-886, with corrections and changes ca. 1996 (Box 5)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Final Version of Part IV, Chapters 63-89, with corrections and changes (2 folders) ca. 1996 (Box 6)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Chapters 1-84, with pencilled corrections (4 folders) n.d. (Box 6)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Chapters 11-89, Renumbered with pencilled corrections (5 folders) n.d. (Box 7)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Chapters 39-56, Pages 450-601, Renumbered & heavily revised n.d. (Box 7)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Chapters 46-52, Pages 466-543, Renumbered. n.d. (Box 8)
- AMs & TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, - New Section called Chapters Between 45 & 46, heavily corrected & revised n.d. (Box 8)
- TMs A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley - Miscellaneous Corrected Chapters & Sections 1996, n.d. (Box 8)
- A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley - Notes to Copy Editor re List of Names & Exotic Wordsca. 1996 (Box 8)
- A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley - Outline of the Book & Explanation of Reason for Writing About Joseph of Arimathea 1995-1996 (Box 8)
- A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley - Research Notebook kept by Ripley ca. 1995-1996 (Box 8)
- A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley - Research Notes & Outlines for the Book ca. 1995-1996 (Box 8)
- AMs (EC) The Saga of Scarlett by Alexandra Ripley n.d. (Box 8)
- print A Love Divine by Alexandra Ripley, Bound Advance Reading Copy 1996 (Box 8)
- TMs Critique of the Original Manuscript of Scarlettn.d. (Box 9)
- TMs Scarlett Story by Jim Henerson and Christopher Lofton, based on a novel by Alexandra Ripley, RHI Productions 1992 May 21 (Box 9)
- TMs Scarlett by Alexandra Ripley, Pages 1-933 (4 folders) ca. 1992 (Box 9)
- TMs Scarlett by Alexandra Ripley, Miscellaneous Pages ca. 1992 (Box 9)
- Jerusalem in the Second Temple Period 1977
- The Temple Mount 70 C.E. A Reconstruction drawing by Martha Ritmeyer based on recent archaeological finds n.d.